MIKE MACKENZIE

mike@veb.co.nz

 $+64\ 027\ 318\ 6847\ ({
m SMS\ only\ please})$

SKILLS

CPM

| PHP, MySQL, HTML and Linux (using tools such as: vim, cron, memcache). | 8 years |
|---|---------|
| E-commerce solutions, including usage of 3rd party payment APIs (PayPal, PayByCash, ShareIt and DPS) | 6 years |
| Development and release of web and desktop based solutions, including marketing before and after release | 3 years |
| Linux server management (sys-admin) | 6 years |
| C# application development and ASP .NET development | 1 year |
| Python to create server-management scripts and stable web-applications. (Django web application framework, and Flask) | 2 years |
| Javascript and jQuery in web-development | 4 years |
| Git and GitHub for source-control. (learned Git before GitHub was released) | 7 years |
| C development (game engine backends) | |
| Bugzilla for bug reporting and contributing to various open source projects | |
| Revenue generation for a product, or website using advertising methods such as C | PA and |

Have built efficient and scalable websites supporting high load and traffic within a budget to maximise revenue.

Experience in social media, including paid advertising campaigns in Facebook and various successful marketing campaigns. Helped various non-profit organizations in IT consulting, including web development and server administration.

EXPERIENCE

The Logic Studio

http://www.logicstudio.co.nz

Dunedin, New Zealand July 2014 - Present

Software Developer

Full-time position

Web Application development, heavy on JavaScript, with PHP5, jQuery, Angular, Bootstrap3. Responsive Web Development, heavy on "mobile-first".

1 recommendation upon request

veb

http://veb.co.nz

Dunedin, New Zealand December 2010 - Present

I do freelance development when the needs arises. I do a lot of work with social media primarily as well as developing tools for specific social media platforms with the goal to make people happy, and at the same time figuring out how to monetise it.

2 recommendations available upon request

University of Otago

http://www.otago.ac.nz

Dunedin, New Zealand 2012 - 2014 (2 years, 6 months)

Senior Web Developer / Applications Programmer for <u>Web Services</u>

Full-time position

Developed multiple small and large scale projects primarily developed using PHP+MySQL using the CodeIgniter Framework (LAMP stack), while learning Laravel for when our servers upgrade to PHP5.3. Used Git and GitLab for source control. Developed and supported websites using Oracle 10g CMS and Oracle DB. Created and maintained E-Commerce websites for conferences, merchandise, enquiries and forms.

Administered and supported the high-volume University Help Desk for issues and concerns related to the University CMS. Founding member of the University's Social Media Advisory Group.

3 recommendations available upon request

The Captioning Working Group

http://www.captionitnz.co.nz/?p=195

Remote part-time work (volunteer) 2014 - 2014 (1 year)

Web Developer / System Administrator / Social Media Marketing / Consultant

For the <u>CaptionItNZ</u> campaign. I helped set up their new website, blog, Facebook Page, and Twitter account. I spent countless hours progressing it to the point where I could hand it over to the other team members,

<u>CaptionItNZ</u> was told that implementing caption support for TVNZ On Demand could cost millions of dollars and thousands of man hours, which led me to developing a very quick proof of concept http://veb.co.nz/caption (demo)

3 recommendations available upon request

South Link Health

http://www.southlink.co.nz

Dunedin, New Zealand 2011 - 2012 (1 year)

Programmer/Analyst in the New Zealand Health Care industry.

Full-time position

Developed and maintained legacy code in C# ASP.NET web applications as well as designing and developing front-ends in jQuery, CSS and HTML5. Created and maintained production websites using Microsoft IIS server 6 and 7. Designed and developed web applications for Microsoft Reporting Services as well as web reports using jQuery charting libraries such as Flot and Highcharts.

Did rapid web application development and used various version control systems for source code control (Git + GitLab, Tortoise, CVS and Mercurial). Scoped projects developed using Agile Methodologies.

1 recommendation available upon request

Nabi Studios Singapore

<u>http://www.nabistudios.com</u> 2006 - 2010 (part-time remote and on-site Singapore)

Software Developer / Community Manager

Primary role was to direct and implement all web solutions and operations for an international game with 40,000 active players. Developed and maintained a virtual economy based on microtransactions for Nabi Studio's flagship game, including product promotions and item creation. Developed and implemented international payment systems to support the virtual economy.

Maintained the dedicated Linux servers used to host the game to ensure no downtime and damage control if necessary. Built and maintained scalable and efficient websites with large traffic by using different servers for database, memcache and static file hosting to ensure fast speeds and flexibility Performed database administration via MySQL+memcached and also developed and maintained C++ game server backends.

Build and cared for the game community which numbered to over 800,000 members and supervised community staff to ensure a better online experience for members. This also included building a social media presence via Youtube, Facebook and Twitter and game blogs.

EDUCATION

Otago Polytechnic

Dunedin, New Zealand

2007 - 2010

Bachelor of Information Technology

Notable achievements

- Best papers: Operating Systems (Linux) and PHP
- ODT (Otago Daily Times) award at graduation

Kings High School

Dunedin, New Zealand

2006

WEB PRESENCE

GitHub page: https://github.com/veb
GitHub gists: https://gist/github.com/veb
LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/vebbed
Personal site: http://www.veb.co.nz

EXCITING PROJECTS

Currently, there's four ongoing personal projects that I'm rather passionate about, so feel free to ask me about any of them!

• Therable

 Android application. Will be making use of Android L and the Moto 360 hopefully.

• Airsign

• Started off as an iOS application, which became mature - but it has since pivoted into "Airsign" and now using the Android -platform.

• PleaseCaption.me

- After I left the Captioning Working Group / the CaptionItNZ campaign, I
 decided I wanted to continue what I started off doing, but with my own vision
 instead: increasing awareness of captioning, and to provide tutorials, articles,
 software and of course, better education regarding the need for captioning
 across all kinds of media.
 - Software to make captioning business YouTube videos, advertisements and other(?) easier for the average business owner.
 - Education on why they should even bother (cost-ratio benefit)
 - Technical documentation for the more technically-inclined people.
 - Using the <u>Ghost Blogging Platform</u> in which we are staying ahead of the curve by creating premium themes, plugins and extensions. Ghost runs using NodeJS and is completely Javascript-orientated.

• New "veb" website

Currently being rebuilt in Jekyll, which is one of more astonishing platforms I
have used for the web recently. Faster and incredibly easy to use. Made mostly
in Javascript and Markdown.